statravel.com.au 2019-03-17

# Privacy policy of STA Travel Australia and New Zealand | STA Travel | Privacy policy

## What information we collect

When you consult us in one of our branches or over the telephone, or provide your details online, we will collect and use personal information that is relevant to you and your travel arrangements (for example, your name and contact details and information about your trip). This use includes providing necessary information to airlines, tour companies, car hire agencies, hotels or insurance providers to fulfil your travel arrangements. By consulting us and providing your personal information to make a booking, or by making a booking, you consent to STA Travel using any personal information for the purpose of making and completing travel arrangements on your behalf.

Promotions that run on our site may be sponsored by companies other than STA Travel, or may be co-sponsored. Some or all data collected during a promotion (including personal information) may be shared with the co-sponsor(s). If data collected is to be shared, you will be notified prior to the time of data collection or transfer. You can decide not to participate in the promotion if you don't want your data to be shared.

When completing an on line job application for a Branch Sales Manager or Travel Adviser, it requires you to complete mandatory fields and provide personal information. STA Travel recognises that the personal information related to your application is highly personal and sensitive. The information will be only used for this purpose. STA Travel may pass your application onto a third party Recruitment Company for initial interviewing. Applications are kept on file for a period of six months.

When you visit the STA Travel web site, we may collect and store information about your visit on an anonymous, aggregate basis. This information may include the time and length of your visit, the pages you looked at on our site and the site you visited just before coming to ours. We may also record the name of your Internet service provider. We only use this information only to measure site activity and to develop ideas for improving our site.

We may collect your personal information directly from you, when you provide it to our staff or to our agents or contractors.  We may also collect personal information about you from publicly available sources, from our related companies or from third parties (for example, from referees if you apply for a job with us, or from our co-sponsors on promotional activities).

## Who is collecting your information

When you are on the site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with STA Travel only, except as otherwise explained in this privacy policy or notified to you at the time. 

## With whom such information will be shared

When you make travel arrangements with STA Travel and provide personal information about yourself, we use this information to complete your travel arrangements and to provide you with promotional information. This may include sharing your personal information with our related entities, and to third parties that provide products and services to us or through us. Some or all of the data collected during a promotion may be shared with the co-sponsor(s) of the promotion. Job application information may be supplied to a third party recruitment company for initial interviewing.

STA Travel may also disclose the personal information that we collect about you when we have reason to believe that it is necessary to identify, contact, investigate and raise concerns about, or bring legal action against, persons or entities who may be causing (or who may in future cause) injury to you, to us or to others.

We may also disclose your personal information if required by law or otherwise permitted by the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) (Privacy Act) or other relevant laws in Australia which relate to the protection of personal information, including any future amendments to those laws (Privacy Laws). To avoid doubt, we may disclose your personal information if permitted by the Australian Privacy Principles under the Privacy Act and any amendments to them.

We may also transfer or disclose your personal information to persons outside of Australia in accordance with this privacy policy (including by contacting overseas airlines, tour companies, car hire agencies, hotels or insurance providers) if your travel arrangements involve overseas travel. In this case, we may transfer or disclose your personal information to relevant persons based or operating in the country/countries in which you are travelling or planning to travel.

We may also transfer or disclose your personal information to our ultimate parent company (Diethelm Keller Ltd) in Switzerland in accordance with this privacy policy.  

## Email subscription opt in and opt out

If you would like to receive news about the latest deals; events and competitions we welcome you to sign-up to our emails. Use this sign up form and note that the only mandatory information required is your name, email address and postcode.

If you subscribe to both our Deals email and Newsletter letter, the frequency of our emails is once a week on average. Very occasionally you will receive more than one per week when there is a late-breaking deal.

You can unsubscribe at any time by simply clicking on the “unsubscribe” link on our emails.

Your email address will only be used for the purpose for which you have provided it and it will not be added to an external mailing list or used for any other purpose without your consent.

## ISIC card information

Information and discounts are correct at time of printing and are subject to change without notice.

## Third party links

The STA Travel site may contain links to web sites operated and maintained by third parties over which we have no control. The information practices of those web sites are not covered by this privacy policy. Any information you provide to third party web sites will be governed under the terms of each such web site's privacy policy. Except to the extent that liability cannot be excluded or limited under applicable law, we have no responsibility or liability whatsoever for the content, actions or policies of third party web sites. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of all third party web sites that link to this site because such privacy policies may be materially different from our privacy policy.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits, in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. 

## Storage and Security

You take on line privacy seriously, and so does STA Travel. It's our way of sustaining your trust in STA travel and our products and services. This means we will take all reasonable measures to ensure your information is secure and have implemented technology for this purpose.

We store personal information on computer databases and/or in hard copy, and we employ reasonable commercial physical and electronic security measures to protect any records that we hold which contain your personal information.  We may also engage third party service providers to assist in storing and processing certain types of personal information for us. Some of these service providers may be located overseas, or use facilities located overseas to provide us with services.

You'll need to enter your email address and nominated password to access the new parts of our site being added, and to be eligible for exclusive prizes and discounts. 

## No Unlawful or Prohibited Use Of This Website

As a condition of your use of this website, you agree that you will not use this website for any purpose that is unlawful or prohibited by these terms and conditions. You agree that you will not perform such actions which would purposely affect the sites performance and stability.

## In summary

STA Travel is committed to protecting your privacy. We use the information we collect on our sites to make our service the best they can be and to enhance your overall experience.  

## Your consent

By using our site, consulting us in one of our branches or over the telephone, or providing your details to make a booking, you consent to the collection and use of this information by STA Travel in accordance with this privacy policy. 

If you choose not to provide your personal information to us for the purposes set out in this privacy policy, we may not be able to undertake certain activities for you such as providing you with requested information, products or services. 

## Feedback, access and corrections

STA Travel welcomes your questions and comments about privacy. Please contact us if you have any queries or concerns, or if you wish to exercise your rights under the Privacy Act to request access to, or to correct or update, your personal information, via the links below. [Contact us here](https://forms-customercare.statravel.com/?division=AU&_ga=2.128556805.823422502.1506421760-257923017.1503484850#/customer_care).

STA Travel reserves the right to alter our privacy policy, as business needs require. Any alterations to this policy will be posted on our website in a timely manner.

## Privacy complaints

If you have a complaint about our collection, use or disclosure of personal information, or if you believe that we have not complied with this Privacy Policy or the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth), please [contact us here](https://forms-customercare.statravel.com/?division=AU&_ga=2.128556805.823422502.1506421760-257923017.1503484850#/customer_care).

When contacting us please provide as much detail as possible in relation to your question, comment or complaint.

STA Travel will take any privacy complaint seriously and any complaint will be assessed by an appropriate person with the aim of resolving any issue in a timely and efficient manner.  We request that you cooperate with us during this process and provide us with any relevant information that we may need.
